Joseph F. Ghanimah

jfghanimah@gmail.com • (630) 670-7606 www.josephghanimah.com

SUMMARY

Exceptionally adaptable Computer Engineering major currently attending the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign with minors in Mathematical Statistics and Data Science. Strong critical and lateral thinking skills with 2+ years of relevant experience with full stack application development and predictive analytics.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign, IL *August 2018 - May 2022*

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering

- Minors: Mathematical Statistics, Data Science
- Awards & Honors: President's Award Program Honors Student, College of Engineering James Scholar
- Activities: Illini Esports Manager & Headcoach

EXPERIENCE

College CoD League Wood Dale, IL

Full-Stack Software Engineer (www.collegecod.com)

June 2018 - Present

- Manage DigitalOcean linux web server with Nginx and Gunicorn
- Design, deploy, and maintain website, using Python (Django), JS, CSS, and HTML
- Identify problems uncovered by testing or customer feedback, and correct problems or refer problems to appropriate personnel for correction
- Develop a PostgreSQL database infrastructure that supports thousands of data entries to enable in-depth player stat tracking
- Document technical factors such as server load, bandwidth, database performance and browser and device types
- Track SEO and web analytics to present with internal development and design teams

G3 Circuit L.L.C. Urbana-Champaign, IL

Founder & Lead Developer

August 2018 - September 2019

- Lead a team of 20+, distributing company's limited resources to ensure goal of expanding competitive play to a wider audience
- Organized 300+ competitors in various matches and tournaments for league season
- Deployed a serverless web application on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) to manage teams and players using Python (Flask), MySQL, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

O'Hare Freight USA Inc.

Bensenville, IL

Night Shift Security Guard

May 2017 - August 2018

- Delivered written and verbal reports of over-night activities and irregularities of industrial premises such as property damage, theft, presence of unauthorized persons, or unusual occurrences
- Inspected and adjusted security systems and equipment to ensure operations use and to detect evidence of tampering

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Project experience with machine learning, cloud computing, automation, and data visualization
- Proficient in Python (Django, Flask, TensorFlow, NumPy)
- Additional familiarity with C++, C#, SQL, Javascript, HTML, and CSS
- Collaborated in small and large team environments using applications like Trello, Slack, Github, and Discord
- Competent with video, photo, and audio editing tools